瑞秋，我只是来…
Oh! Hey,Rach.I was just coming over here to...
我不必骗你，你搬走了
Wait,I don't have to lie to you,you don't live here anymore.
我在吃他们的东西，你呢？
I'm eating their food. You?
罗斯跟我妹约会 窗帘已经拉上2个半小时了
Ross is on a date with my sister. They shut the drapes two hours ago.
我不知道我们还能跟你妹妹约会喔
I didn't know we could date your sister.
乔伊，我们知道你在偷东西吃
We know you steal our food.
不用了
I'm good.
窗帘还没拉开？
Drapes still closed?
对，其实隔两户的变态老夫妇 才应该拉窗帘
Yeah. That perverted couple two doors over should've shut theirs.
那是秋千吗？ 不要问
-Is that a swing? -Oh,don't even ask.
好恶
Yuck
罗斯居然跟瑞秋的妹妹约会
I can't believe Ross is with her sister.
钱德亲了我妹妹 我气了他10年
When Chandler kissed my sister,I was mad for 10 years.
那是5年前的事 对，还有5年
-That was five years ago. -You got five years left.
乔伊… 你想再加1年吗？
-Joey.. -Want to make it six?
本集播出：“钱德不会哭”
The One Where Chandler Can't Cry
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
罗斯，你好吗？你在这里
Oh,Ross,hey. Hi,how are you? There you are.
一杯咖啡
Can I get a cup of coffee?
昨晚的约会怎样啊？
So how was your big date last night?
还不错，很开心
It was okay. It was fun.
是吗？太好了
It was fun? Great.
所以你们合得来吗？
So did you guys hit it off?
应该吧
I guess so.
所以你们有怎样吗？ 听说你们把窗帘拉上了
So did anything happen? Rumor has it you guys shut the drapes.
我们没怎样
No. No. Nothing happened.
我是要放我最爱的化石幻灯片
I shut the drapes to show her slides of my favorite fossils.
幻灯片…所以看来你们真的没怎样
Oh,slides!So really nothing happened
我们可以会怎样 她很喜欢我的幻灯片
Something could've happened.She really dug my slides.
而且她绝对有对我放电
And she was definitely giving me the vibe.
是“别再给我看三叶虫照片” 的电吗？
Was it the "Please don't show me another picture of a trilobite" vibe?
她喜欢我，好吗？
I'm telling you,she was in to me,okay?
你还记得三叶虫
Hey,you remembered trilobite.
总之…要是她不喜欢我 为什么要再约我？
Anyway...If she wasn't into me,why would she ask me out again?
她又约你了？ 对
-She asked you out again? -Yeah.
明天晚上，情人节 一年当中最浪漫的日子
Tomorrow night. Valentine's Day. The most romantic day of the year.
谁晓得会怎样
Who knows what could happen.
到时我拉窗帘 或许不是要放幻灯片，你懂吧
I might not be shutting my drapes to show her my slides.
好好好好好我懂我懂我懂 我不能接受你跟我妹交往
Okay! I got it,I got it.I can't go with the "you and my sister" thing.
我就是不能 那样太奇怪了，好吗？
It's just too weird,all right?
一想到你们在一起我就捉狂 我会疯掉，我受不了我受不了
I imagine the two of you together.It just freaks me out. I can't do it!
没事的
It's okay.
如果你受不了，我就不再见她 谢谢你
It's too weird for you. I won't see her again.Thank you.
我是说过了明晚之后
After tomorrow night.
不不不，求求你我受不了 我真的会捉狂
No! I can't do it. It's gonna freak me out!
好，我今晚就告诉她 我不能再跟她见面
Okay. I'll tell her tonight I can't see her anymore.
谢谢
Ross,thanks.
你要我现在打给她吗？ 不用…
Want me to call her now?Oh,no. No,no,no.
那样太夸张了
No. Come on,I mean,that's crazy.
怎样啊？你最近在干嘛？
So,what's going on with you?
我这学期可能会再开一堂课
I may teach another class this semester.
好，现在就打给她
Do it now. Call her now.
我最喜欢这段了 我也是
-This is my favorite part. -Me too.
你们难过什么？又不会有事
I don't know what you guys are so sad about. It all works out.
他会留在小男孩身边 他们会相亲相爱直到永远
E.T. stays with Elliott,and they get to be best friends forever.
乔伊，你看过这部电影 ET回外太空去了
You've seen this movie before,E.T. goes back home.
什么？
What?
我忘了
Oh,no,I forgot.
你们知道什么更催泪？ “小鹿斑比”
You know what's sadder than this? Bambi.
那部片让我哭了3天 不，是2天
I cried for three days with that movie. No,two.
第三天我妈自杀了 我也在为那件事而哭
The third day my mom killed herself,so I was partly crying for that.
哭ET就算了 “小鹿斑比”是卡通耶
Well,that I can see crying over,but Bambi is a cartoon.
斑比的母亲死了你没哭？
You didn't cry when Bambi's mother died?
动画师不再画母鹿 的确很可怜
Yes,it was very sad when the guy stopped drawing the deer.
你们哭成这样，干脆转台好吗 好
If this movie's making you guys cry so much,let's just change the channel.
好了
There.
乔伊，那是多力多滋的广告
Joey,you're crying over a Doritos commercial.
我有去试镜
I was up for that part.
钱德，哭没什么不对 你不必老是那么男子汉
It's okay to cry. You don't have to be macho all the time.
我哪有男子汉 也对
I'm not macho.Yeah,you're right.
我不知道我在想什么
I don't know what I was thinking.
反正我就是没哭过 我不是那种会哭的人
I just never really cried. I'm not a crying kind of guy.
你总会遇见令你鼻酸的事 像…
Come on,there's gotta be something that gets you choked up. Like...
如果你看到一只三脚小狗呢？
What if you saw a three-legged puppy?
我是会难过，但是不会哭
I'd be sad,sure.But I wouldn't cry.
要是那只小狗说 “钱德救救我”
What if the puppy said,"Help me,Chandler
“其他的狗狗都欺负我”
All the other puppies pick on me."
哭？我发现一只会说话的狗 我发了
Cry? I just found a talking puppy. I'm rich!
我知道了…你小时候的照片 你看了一定会哭
I've got it. I have got it.Pictures from your childhood.This'll get you going good.
那张是什么？
Oh,what's going on there?
那是一年级的家长日 我和校警马丁的合照
Parents' Day. First grade.That's me with the janitor,Martin.
你爸妈呢？ 他们不想去
-Where are your parents? -They didn't want to come.
钱德 好可怜喔
-Chandler! -Poor thing.
这件事不会让你哭吗？
That story doesn't make you cry?
不会，我就是不会哭 这没什么，好吗？
No. Look,I don't cry. It's not a big deal,okay?
不，不好，一点也不好
No! It's not okay!It's not okay at all!
你的心是死的
You're dead inside!
请问一下，你是菲比布菲吗？ 是
-Excuse me? -Yeah?-Are you Phoebe Buffay? -Yeah.
你可以帮我签名吗？ 我最崇拜你了
Can I get your autograph? I'm your biggest fan.
你最崇拜我了？ 我一直想认识你
My biggest fan? I've always wanted to meet you.
没问题
Sure. Yeah.
谢谢你，我只想说 你真的很有天分
Wow. Wow,thanks a lot.I just want to say,I think you're really talented.
你是因为崇拜我才这么说
You're just saying that because you're my biggest fan.
乔伊，好好招呼那个人 他是个粉丝
Take good care of that guy. He's a fan.
再见
Bye.
你看过我演的“我们的日子”？
So you saw me on Days of Our Lives,huh?
要我来一段雷莫瑞医生吗？
You want me to do a little Dr. Drake Ramoray for you?
我不知道你在说什么 不过我刚拿到菲比布菲的签名
I have no idea what you're talking about.But I just got Phoebe Buffay's autograph.
你是菲比的粉丝 没错，她的电影我都看过
Oh. You're Phoebe's fan.Oh,yeah. I've seen all her movies.
电影？ 那是菲比布菲，色情明星
-Movies? -That was Phoebe Buffay,the porn star.
不是吧 是，她演过“性玩具总动员2”（模仿《玩具总动员》）
I don't think so.No,it was. She was in Sex Toy Story Two...
“阿拉比亚的劳伦斯”（模仿《阿拉伯的劳伦斯》）
Lawrence of a Labia.
而我拿到她的签名 漫画店的人一定不会相信
And I got her autograph.The guys at the comic book store won't believe this.
甘瑟，以后别让那个人进来 他说菲比是色情明星
Gunther?Don't let that guy in here anymore. He said Phoebe's a porn star.
说明星太夸张了 不过她真的很猛
Well,I wouldn't call her a star,but she's really good.
你应该去看“检查她的加杰特”（模仿《神探加杰特》）
You should check out Inspect Her Gadget.
说了你一定不信 罗斯刚刚回绝我，又没说原因
Ross just totally blew me off,and he didn't even tell me why.
忘掉一个男人最好的办法 就是跟别人交往
The best thing to do to get over a guy is to start dating someone else.
我们公司有个鲍伯你一定喜欢 他是人力资源部的明日之星
Oh! There is this great guy you will just love at work,named Bob.He's a real up-and-comer in Human Resources.
也许我太说得太多了 也许我应该在性方面更主动些
Maybe I talk too much,or maybe I should have been more aggressive sexually.
不不不…
No,no,no.
不要，罗斯不吃那套
No,that would never have worked on Ross.
不过你知道谁可能会心动？ 人力资源部的鲍伯
But you know who that might work on? Bob in Human Resources.
谢谢你 但我不要跟你的某个同事随便交往
Thanks,but I'm not gonna date some random guy from your work.
不是随便，是鲍伯
Not random. Bob.
可能是因为我不够成熟 不够聪明
It's probably because I'm not mature enough or smart enough...
或许他不喜欢我的打扮…
Maybe he doesn't like the way I dress.
不可能的，一定是我不够聪明
No,that can't be it. It's gotta be the smart thing.
我好笨 我是个美得冒泡的笨女人
I'm so stupid. I'm just this,like,incredibly pretty,stupid girl.
不是这样的亲爱的…好吧 你知道罗斯为何取消约会？
No,honey.Okay.Okay. You want to know why Ross canceled the date?
是我要求的
Because I asked him to.
你要求的？为什么？
You asked him to?
因为你是我妹妹 而罗斯和我有一大段渊源
-Why? -Because you are my sister...and Ross and I have this huge history.
我不懂，你想跟罗斯交往吗？ 不想
-You want to go out with Ross? -No.
你不要他，又不要我拥有他？
You don't want him,but you don't want me to have him?
人力资源部的鲍伯…
You know,Bob in Human Resources...
你居然这样对我 你害我怀疑我的智商
I can't believe you did this! You had me doubting how smart I was!
你害我怀疑我的穿着品味
You had me doubting my fashion sense!
我只是叫你不要跟罗斯约会 世上的男人那么多，你…
It's not that big a deal. Just don't date Ross. There's other..
你没有资格教我做事
You have no right to tell me what to do.
我不是在教你做 我是在教你不要做
I'm not telling you what to do. I am telling you what not to do!
你为什么老是这么嫉妒我？
Why are you so jealous of me?
不是我嫉妒你 是你任性，不能吃还想吃
This is not about me being jealous.It's about you being a brat,wanting what you can't have.
不能吃？
Can't have?
很抱歉 我不能吃的东西只有乳制品
Excuse me. The only thing I can't have is dairy!
好，你和鲍伯的事吹了
Well,you just blew your chances at dating Bob!
谁？ 人力资源部的啦
-Who? -With Human Resources!
我嫉妒她？她以为她是谁？ 卡罗琳公主（摩纳哥公主）吗？
Jealous of her? Who does she think she is,Princess Caroline?
你嫉妒卡罗琳公主？ 我有自己的城堡吗？
-You're jealous of Princess Caroline? -Do I have my own castle?
菲比不在吧？ 不在
Hey.Phoebe's not here,is she? -No.
真好，你们租了片子？
Did you get a movie?
对，但是你们应该不会喜欢
Yeah. Yeah.But I don't think it's the kind you're gonna like.
你该不会又租那种 会消耗面纸的片子吧？
Not more movies that'll have us reaching for the tissues all night?
可以这么说
Sort of.
到底怎么了？
What's going on?
菲比是色情明星
Phoebe's a porn star!
什么？是的。你们在说什么啊
-What? -Yeah!What are you talking about?
“菲比布菲之布菲与吸血鬼同眠”（模仿《吸血鬼猎人巴菲》）
"Phoebe Buffay in Buffay The Vampire Layer."
天哪 这是菲比，你在哪里租的？
That's Phoebe. Where did you get that?
布里克街的成人录影带店
At the adult video place on Bleecker.
我看到乔伊正要进去 我就提前进去了想给他个惊喜
And I saw Joey was about to go in,so I ran in ahead of him...to surprise him.
然后我又假装不知道他也在
Then I pretended that I didn't know he was in there.
天哪，我真是不敢相信
Wow. I mean,I just can't believe this.
真是知人知面不知心 虽然菲比一直是个问号
I mean,you think you know someone.Even Phoebe,who's always been somewhat of a question mark.
好诡异喔
This is so bizarre.
不过毕竟她的童年那么悲惨
I guess it makes sense. She had such a terrible childhood.
我童年悲惨也没去拍A片
I had a bad childhood and I don't do porn.
对，但是你的心死了
Yes,but you're dead inside.
我还是拿去还吧 为为为什么？
I'd better take that back.What,why? Why?
我们不能看，那是菲比演的
We can't watch it. It's Phoebe.
你说得对，我们不该看 没错
We shouldn't watch this.Absolutely not. That goes back.
看一点好了 前半段就好
-Maybe a bit. -The first half?
这样是不对的 菲比是我们的朋友
This is wrong,you guys! Phoebe's our friend!
我不要看 没错，够义气
-I'm not gonna watch it. -Yeah!Good for you,Joe.
我就知道你在这里 纳斯佛拉吐
I thought I'd find you here,Nosferatool.
布菲，你要把你的尖棍 深深插进我的体内吗？
Are you going to plunge your stake into my dark places?
其实我有点希望是你来插
Actually,I was kind of hoping it would be the other way around.
等等，她的脚踝上是什么？ 你在看她的脚踝？
What's that on her ankle?Her ankle is what you're watching?
很难看得出来…
Well,it's hard to tell.
她能不能不要动了
God,if she would just stop moving.
她只是在工作
She's just doing her job.
你们这些变态
You sick bastards!
是刺青，怪了，菲比没…
It's a tattoo.That's weird. Phoebe doesn't..
是乌苏拉啦 那不是菲比，是乌苏拉
Wait,that's Ursula! That's not Phoebe! That is Ursula!
倒带倒带 我可以看了，快倒带
Wait,wait! I can watch that! Rewind it! Rewind it!
你们在干嘛？
Hey.What's up?
天哪！我在干什么？
Oh,my God! What am I doing?!
亲爱的
Hey,sweetie.
“心灵鸡汤”？
"Chicken Soup for the Soul"?
这张沙发背后是空的
There's no back to this couch.
你看它干嘛？你讨厌这种书 我想试试看
You hate this kind of stuff.I figured I'd give it a shot.
也许有某个故事会让我哭 你就不会觉得我的心死了
One of the stories may make me cry,then you won't think I'm dead inside.
你真有心
Oh,that's so sweet.
但你不会哭也无所谓，我爱你
I don't care if you can't cry. I love you.
这话温暖了我空空如也的胸口（《绿野仙踪》中铁皮人的台词）
Oh,that makes me feel so warm in my hollow tin chest.
别闹了
Stop it.
你想嘛，哪天我们结婚了 来到神父面前，我却这样
Seriously. We get married,I'm up at the altar and I'm like this:
我不在乎 因为我知道你内心会充满喜悦
I won't care.I know that you'll be feeling it all in here.
是吗？ 当然
-Yeah? -Yeah.
要是有一天我们生小孩 医生在产房把宝宝交给你
And if we have a baby one day and the doctor hands it to you in the delivery room
而你没有哭，那又怎样？
and you don't cry,so what?
要是我们送他去念大学 回家第一次看到他的空房
If we take him to college and come home...and we see his empty room for the first time
而你却没反应…我也不在意
and you got nothing?It won't matter to me.
好，那我就不那么担心了
Okay.I won't worry about this anymore then.
要是我死了
And then,you know,if I die...
久病弃世，你在写哀悼词
from a long illness...and you're writing my eulogy
结果打开抽屉 看到我留了一张字条写道
and you open the desk drawer and find a note from me that says:
“我会永远与你同在”
"I will always be with you"...
而你还是挤不出一滴眼泪 我会知道你的心早已泪流成河
and you still can't shed one tiny tear?I know you'll be crying a river inside.
我爱你… 你是怎么搞的？
-I love you. -What is wrong with you?!
什么？ 你居然无法为亡妻流一滴泪
-What? -What?You can't shed a tear for your dead wife?
我死后留了字条给你耶
I left you a note from the beyond!
所以刚才都不是真心话？ 废话，你这个机器人
-So you didn't mean any of that? -No,you robot!
死小孩！再乱按电铃我就…
You damn kids! You ring my bell one more time and I swear..
吉儿 我在跟走廊那头的小朋友玩
Oh,Jill!That's a game I play with the kids down the hall.
他们越来越喜欢我
They've really taken a liking to me.
有什么事吗？
What's the matter?
瑞秋和我大吵一架 我可以进去吗？
Rachel and I had a big fight. Can I come in?
我知道我们不能再见面 我也可以接受
I know we're not supposed to see each other anymore.
只是我人生地不熟 又很需要找个人谈一谈
I don't know anybody in this city and I need somebody to talk to.
好啊，怎么了？ 我不想谈
Sure. What happened?I don't want to talk about it.
好…
Okay.
不过有件事会让我比较开心
-You know what might cheer me up? -What?
什么事？ 再多看几张你的超酷幻灯片
Seeing some more of your super cool slides.
真的吗？ 绝对的，我爱死了
-Wow,really? -Totally. I loved them.
你还可以继续讲解 那几种不同的沙子
You could finish telling me about the different kinds of sand.
没问题，你等一下 我去拿投影机和讲义
I'd love to. Wait right here,I'll go get the projector and my notes.
太好了，谢谢你 你真是个好朋友
Thanks. You're such a good friend.
你们有看到吉儿吗？ 我到处都找不到她
Have you guys seen Jill? I can't find her.
没看到
-No.
罗斯在家吗？我打去问他好了
-Is Ross home?Maybe I'll call him and see if he's seen her..
哪一位？ 是菲比…菲比
Who is it?It's Phoebe..."Phoebe"!
天哪
-Hey! -Oh,God!
所以你在拍A片 我没有
So you're making porn movies.No,I'm not.
摄影机还在转 你现在就在拍
We're still rolling!You're making one right now!
菲比快点 而且还用我的名字
Let's go,Phoebe.And you're using my name.
对，有什么事吗？
Can I help you with something?
菲比，快点 我在跟别人说话…
Phoebe,come on!Look,I'm talking right now.
你是在叫她，噢
You mean her. Oh.
双胞胎的题材一向很热卖 什么？
You know,twin stuff is always a real big seller.What?
我可以帮你谈到30块钱
I could talk them into giving you...thirty dollars.
不要！想都别想
No! No way! No!
而且别再冒用我的名字 你真丢脸
And stop using my name! And shame on you!
你们都很丢脸，你们恶心死了 尤其是你，和你的那个
And shame on all of you! You're disgusting!Especially you,with that!
幻灯片快好了
The slides are almost ready.
好…我知道还少了什么：酒
Yeah.I know what this is missing:Alcohol.
好，厨房有红酒 太好了
There's wine in the kitchen.Oh,great.
我妹妹为什么在你家？ 窗帘为什么拉上了？
What is my sister doing there,and why are the drapes shut?
好，你别激动 她心情很差，我们只是在聊天
Okay. Rach,calm down,okay?She's really upset. We're just talking.
罗斯，她想藉由跟你发生关系 来报复我
She's making something happen with you to get back at me.
所以她来只是为了这个？
That's the only reason she could be here,huh?
会不会是因为我很善于倾听 放的幻灯片很好看
It couldn't be that maybe I'm a good listener...and I put on a great slide show?
罗斯，是真的 她在利用你来报复我
Ross,I am telling you,she is using you to get back at me.
我自己可以应付 回头再聊，再见
I think I can take care of myself. I'll talk to you later. Goodbye.
是你姐打来的 她觉得你在利用我
That was your sister,actually.She thinks you're just using me.
所以呢？
So?
我刚去过乌苏拉的公司
I just came from the company Ursula works for.
连你也做了
Oh,no,not you too?
不，我是去领菲比布菲的支票 有很多张喔
I went to get Phoebe Buffay's checks. There were a lot of them.
漂亮
Nice!
而且我不必再去了 因为我留了我的“正确”地址
And I won't have to go back there anymore...because I gave them my "correct address."
太好了，但别人还是会误会 你不会困扰吗？
Isn't it gonna bother you that people think you're a porn star?
不会，我有办法
Oh,no,I know how to handle it.
是吗？ 没错
-Good. -Yeah.
想知道你在哪里见过我？
Trying to figure out how you know me?
给你一个提示：A片！好吗？
I'll give you a hint. From porn!
没错，你的变态男朋友 在A片里看过我
Yeah,your pervert boyfriend watched me in a porno movie!
看吧
-See? -Yeah.
你对吉儿的看法或许没错
You may have been right about Jill.
我就知道！怎么了？
I knew it! What happened?
她吻了我 什么？你们亲嘴了？
She kissed me.What? You kissed?
也许我们应该回避一下
Maybe we should give them some privacy...
我尽量不去亲她
Look,I tried not to kiss her,okay?
听起来可不是 想不亲一个人的话，不要亲就对了
Doesn't sound like it. It's easy not to kiss someone.You just don't.
我们现在就没有亲嘴
Look at us right now,not kissing!
让我说完好吗？ 她过来亲我，我没有阻止
Let me finish,okay? She started kissing me...and I didn't stop it.
我没有多想
I guess I just wasn't thinking.
是啊，没有多想 我来让你好好想一想
Yeah. Let me give you something to think about.
慢着，但是后来我一想就把她推开了
Hold on! But then I started thinking and I stopped the kissing.
谢谢你把舌头 从我妹的嘴里缩回来告诉我
Thank you for taking your tongue out of my sister's mouth to tell me that.
我是想到如果我跟吉儿怎样 我们就再也不能怎样了
I realized if anything happened with me and Jill...then nothing could ever happen with us.
什么？
-What?
我是说 我不知道我们还会不会怎样
-No,I mean...I don't know if anything is ever going to happen with us...again,ever.
但我不想断绝这个可能性 于是我喊停，然后…
But I don't want to know that it never could.So I stopped it
她气得摔坏我的投影机
and she got mad and broke my projector.
我都不知道该说什么了
I don't even know what to say.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
我的天哪，你在哭吗？ 这两个人为何就是不能在一起
My God,are you crying?I just don't see why those two can't work things out!
好，我要走了
All right,I'm leaving.
我要远离某个一直害我的人
I'm not spending one more day with someone who's out to sabotage me.
就是你，瑞秋
That's you,Rachel.
我知道
Yeah,I got that.
还有你，我投怀送抱你却不要 你真够同性恋的
And you! I throw myself at you...and you say no? How gay are you?
你自己保重
You take care,Jill.
好，我要走了 别替我担心，我会自立自强
Okay,I'm leaving. Don't worry about me,I'll make it on my own.
就算我很茫然 不知该怎么活下去
Who knows how I'll get by,or even if I'll survive.
吉儿，别装了 我知道你跟爸和好了
You can stop that now,I know you made up with Daddy.
你怎么知道？ 猜的，而且你的礼车到了
-You do? How? -Oh,just a wild guess...and your limo just pulled up.
我还来不及多认识你们 真可惜
-Sorry I didn't get to know you guys better. -Absolute shame.
好，再见 再见
-Okay,see you. -Bye-bye.
吉儿居然走了
I can't believe Jill's gone.
没办法，我一发不可收拾
I can't help it,I opened a gate!